{
    "title": "quiz 4 : chapter 3",
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is correct about execution cycle of an instruction?",
        "options": [
          "Decode operation code (opcode), calculate operand address, fetch operand, execute operation, calculate address of operand and store operand",
          "Fetch instruction, decode opcode, calculate operand address, fetch operand, execute operation, calculate address of operand and store operand",
          "Read instruction, decode opcode, calculate operand address, fetch operand, execute operation, calculate address of operand and store operand",
          "Decode operation code (opcode), calculate operand address, fetch operand, execute operation, calculate address of operand and display operand"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following are the layers of the QPI protocol architecture?",
        "options": [
          "Physical layer, link layer, routing layer, protocol layer",
          "Physical layer, link layer, routing layer and virtual layer",
          "Physical layer, link layer, network layer and protocol layer",
          "Physical layer, link layer, runtime layer and protocol layer"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "The PCIe point-to-point interconnection structure stands for?",
        "options": [
          "Peripheral Component Interchange Express",
          "Peripheral Component Intermediate Express",
          "Peripheral Component Interconnect Express",
          "Peripheral Component Interconnect Exchange"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following are the layers of the PCIe protocol architecture?",
        "options": [
          "Physical layer, control link and transmission",
          "Physical layer, data link and transfer",
          "Physical layer, data link and transmission",
          "Physical layer, address link and transmission"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is incorrect about von Neumann architecture?",
        "options": [
          "Data and instructions are stored in a single read-write memory",
          "Contents of memory are addressable by location",
          "Data and instructions are stored in the central processing unit",
          "Program execution is sequential"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is correct about an instruction cycle that includes an interrupt cycle?",
        "options": [
          "Processor fetches and execute an instruction, and processor checks to see if an interrupt has occurred",
          "Processor fetches and execute an instruction, processor suspends the current program and processor checks to see if an interrupt has occurred",
          "Processor fetches and execute an instruction, processor fetches the first instruction of the interrupt handler and processor resume the execution of the user program",
          "Processor fetches and execute an instruction, processor fetches the first instruction of the interrupt handler and processor checks to see if an interrupt has occurred."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "Contemporary computer designs are based on one of the following architectures.",
        "options": [
          "Harvard architecture",
          "von Neumann architecture",
          "ARM architecture",
          "PRISC architecture"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following represent the types of instructions executed by a computer?",
        "options": [
          "Data storage, data processing and control",
          "Data transfer, data processing and data storage",
          "Data transfer, data processing and storage",
          "Data transfer, data processing and control"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is incorrect about the fetch cycle of an instruction execution?",
        "options": [
          "Program counter (PC) indicates the address of the next instruction to be fetched",
          "Instruction is fetch and save into the instruction register (IR)",
          "Instruction is fetched and saved into an I/O buffer",
          "PC is incremented after instruction is fetched"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a reason why designers of computers replaced the bus interconnection structure with the point-to-point interconnection structure?",
        "options": [
          "Electrical constraints with increasing the frequency of wide synchronous buses",
          "Difficult to timely synchronize and arbitrate the use of buses at higher data rates",
          "Difficulty to increase bus data rate and reduce bus latency/delay in multicore chips, with multiple processors and significant memory on a single chip.",
          "Reduced number of bus lines for transferring data at higher rate in multicore chips"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following defines the concept of direct memory access (DMA)?",
        "options": [
          "Processor grants to the operating system the authority to read from or write directly to memory.",
          "Processor grants to a user program the authority to read from or write directly to memory.",
          "Processor grants to an interrupt handler the authority to read from or write directly to memory.",
          "Processor grants to an I/O module the authority to read from or write directly to memory."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following defines an interrupt?",
        "options": [
          "Mechanism used to stop the normal processing of the processor by modules such I/O and memory",
          "Mechanism used to interrupt the normal processing of the processor by modules such I/O and memory",
          "Mechanism used to suspend the normal processing of the processor by modules such I/O and memory",
          "Mechanism used to start the normal processing of the processor by modules such I/O and memory"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is a hardware interrupt?",
        "options": [
          "Attempt to execute an illegal machine instruction, or reference outside a userâ€™s allowed memory space",
          "Arithmetic overflow or division by zero",
          "Power failure or memory parity error",
          "Request by I/O controller to signal normal completion of an operation or a variety of error conditions."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following are the characteristics of the point-to-point interconnection structure?",
        "options": [
          "Multiple indirect transmission, layered protocol architecture, packetized data transfer",
          "Multiple direct transmission, layered protocol architecture, packetized data transfer",
          "Multiple direct transmission, stacked protocol architecture, packetized data transfer",
          "Multiple direct transmission, layered protocol architecture, stacked data transfer"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following are the types of transfers supported by an interconnection structure?",
        "options": [
          "Processor to memory, memory to processor, processor to I/O, I/O to processor, I/O to or from memory",
          "Processor to memory, memory to processor, register to processor, processor to register, processor to I/O, I/O to processor, I/O to or from memory",
          "Processor to memory, memory to processor, processor to I/O, I/O to processor, I/O to or from memory, register to I/O, I/O to register",
          "Processor to memory, memory to processor, processor to I/O, I/O to processor, I/O to or from memory, register to memory, memory to register"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following represents the way the processor deals with multiple interrupts?",
        "options": [
          "Disable interrupts while a program is being processed and define priorities for interrupts and to allow an interrupt of higher priority to cause a lower-priority interrupt handler to be itself interrupted",
          "Disable interrupts while an interrupt is being processed and define priorities for programs and to allow a program of higher priority to cause a lower-priority program to be itself interrupted",
          "Disable interrupts while an interrupt is being processed and define priorities for interrupts and to allow an interrupt of higher priority to cause a lower-priority interrupt handler to be itself interrupted",
          "Disable interrupts while an interrupt is being processed and define priorities for interrupts and to prevent an interrupt of higher priority to cause a lower-priority interrupt handler to be itself interrupted"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following are the characteristics of the bus interconnection structure?",
        "options": [
          "Pathway connecting two or more devices, shared data transmission medium, multiple devices connect to the bus",
          "Pathway connecting two devices, shared transmission medium, multiple devices connect to the bus",
          "Pathway connecting two or more devices, shared transmission medium, multiple devices connect to the bus",
          "Pathway connecting two or more devices, shared transmission medium, multiple CPU connect to the bus"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following are the common classes of interrupts?",
        "options": [
          "Program, timer, memory and hardware",
          "Program, timer, I/O and register",
          "Program, timer, CPU and hardware",
          "Program, timer, I/O and hardware"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following defines the steps of an instruction cycle?",
        "options": [
          "Fetch, decode and execution",
          "Fetch and execution",
          "Fetch, store, decode and execution",
          "Fetch, decode, execution and storage"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following are the advantages of point-to-point interconnection structure?",
        "options": [
          "Low latency, higher data rate and better scalability",
          "Higher latency, higher data rate and better scalability",
          "Low latency, low data rate and better scalability",
          "Low latency, higher data rate and reduced scalability"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0
      }
    ]
  }
  